<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<anime id="23" restricted="false">
<type>TV Series</type>
<episodecount>26</episodecount>
<startdate>1998-04-03</startdate>
<enddate>1999-04-24</enddate>
<titles>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="main">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="synonym">Ковбой Бибоп ТВ</title>
<title xml:lang="ar" type="synonym">راعي البقر بيبوب</title>
<title xml:lang="nl" type="synonym">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="lt" type="synonym">Kaubojus Bebopas</title>
<title xml:lang="lt" type="synonym">Kaubojus Bibopas</title>
<title xml:lang="tr" type="synonym">Kovboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="synonym">CBB</title>
<title xml:lang="uk" type="synonym">Ковбой Бібоп ТБ</title>
<title xml:lang="fa" type="synonym">کابوی بیباپ</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">Bebop TV</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">CB</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="official">カウボーイビバップ</title>
<title xml:lang="zh" type="official">星际牛仔</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="de" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="fr" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="it" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="es" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="ko" type="official">카우보이 비밥</title>
<title xml:lang="pl" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="pt" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="pt-BR" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="ca" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="cs" type="official">Kovboj Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="fi" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="he" type="official">קאובוי ביבופ</title>
<title xml:lang="hu" type="official">Csillagközi fejvadászok</title>
<title xml:lang="ro" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
<title xml:lang="bg" type="official">Марсиански каубой</title>
<title xml:lang="es-LA" type="official">Cowboy Bebop</title>
</titles>
<relatedanime>
<anime id="219" type="Side Story">Cowboy Bebop: Tengoku no Tobira</anime>
</relatedanime>
<similaranime>
<anime id="1543" approval="249" total="303">Samurai Champloo</anime>
<anime id="53" approval="139" total="172">Trigun</anime>
<anime id="171" approval="101" total="129">Seihou Bukyou Outlaw Star</anime>
<anime id="3395" approval="94" total="166">Black Lagoon</anime>
<anime id="4906" approval="19" total="62">Darker Than Black: Kuro no Keiyakusha</anime>
<anime id="5779" approval="14" total="37">Michiko to Hatchin</anime>
<anime id="449" approval="13" total="31">Wolf`s Rain</anime>
<anime id="9031" approval="10" total="20">Lupin the Third: Mine Fujiko to Iu Onna</anime>
<anime id="1003" approval="9" total="34">Gungrave</anime>
<anime id="421" approval="7" total="16">Lupin Sansei</anime>
<anime id="4327" approval="3" total="12">Coyote Ragtime Show</anime>
<anime id="403" approval="2" total="17">Lost Universe</anime>
<anime id="412" approval="2" total="8">Z.O.E Dolores,i</anime>
<anime id="1209" approval="2" total="3">Gun Frontier</anime>
<anime id="21" approval="1" total="14">Full Moon o Sagashite</anime>
<anime id="78" approval="1" total="10">Metropolis</anime>
</similaranime>
<recommendations total="84">
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="572441">Best anime ever!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="466624">This is a really good show for adults and I love it. There are many genre(s) included in the show that might just be your fave. There`s comedy, lots of action and thriller, and some horror themes. Trust me. If you like violence, then you will like Cowboy Bebop.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="134273">Anime  is  easily  the  best  of the  1990s  and  its  an  all time  favorite</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="556870">A definite classic anime, maybe THE classic anime for its time period.
Many say that its a masterpiece of a show, and I can agree to an extent.
The episodes preceding the last two is all just following the lives of the characters, all to pay off at the end.
Those two episodes are the masterpiece, the rest is just entertainent of no real value on a single episode basis.
But it all comes down to the end.
As Arkada would say "The ending is paramount"</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="309932">awesome anime, great watch and with some heavy episodes they follow up with some lighthearted antics. But don`t be fooled, there is a deep back story. Does leave you wanting more. You have been warned</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="259764">Might seem retro by today`s standards but I this series has a wonderful story line with fantastic supporting music.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="433878">I can see why this show appeals to so many people, but I can`t pull myself to classify it as a masterpiece.
The production values are high, so as the overall quality. But the episodic nature of it leads to some highs and lows in the enjoyment factor. Not that the latter are unpleasant, its just that the flow becomes somewhat uneven. You will love with a passion some of the episodes, and quickly forget about the others.
Despite those shortcomings it is now one of the few shows that I will recommend to anyone who wants to see what the Anime universe is all about.
The plot is easy to follow, the characters are lovable - and the number of them is easily manageable - and the western influences make it more approachable to everyone.
For newcomers this is a must watch; for veterans it is recommended.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="179096">1st Anime i bought the Full Dvds of thats as high as it gets for me. Aged very well so far and the plot is still deep. The music is still TOP</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="386453">I really liked this anime, but i`m not in the pool of calling thisa masterpiece or the best anime.
Although i can see why Cowboy Bebop is liked so much (lovable characters,  SciFi-Western scenery, smehow an easy plot) it still has it`s flaws.

For me there were too many questions unanswered and way too many episodes you`ll like, but still be wondering, why the hell they are there...
The whole plot and character development could be put into a series with 10 episodes and you wouldn`t miss a thing...

Still great and legendary anime you need to watch.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="345091">rly nice</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="391443">personally, it`s my favorite anime of them all - indisputably revolutionary, lingeringly subtle, thoroughly entertaining, beautifully animated, orchestrated, and directed.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="197514">Simply unrepeatable</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="54199">Great! :D</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="586055">True Masterpiece. Best Anime in History. No need to say more.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="176136">The best anime series of all time</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="230513">Totaly a 10. A must see, the story is great and I fell in love with the music everytime I watch it.....Wat are ya waiting for go SEE it already!

Dp</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="497940">What to say... It was amazing. The story telling was well done; The action was exemplary; The character felt real; And over all it was enjoyable to watch.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="422137">Best developed characters than any other series out there.If you love classic music and noir touch,you should definitely watch this.You will never forget about it after you`ve finished it.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="273473">Simply put, one of the best anime shows ever. It manages to avoid many anime stereotypes that push away first-timers and crafts an extremely engaging world with unique characters and clever plot lines. If someone was to watch one, and only one anime series, this should be it.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="517106">I would definitely recommend the music and story of this great show. Didn`t like the ending but that is just because i don`t like ending with...</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="550129">Adventures, beautiful women and jazz. When the last episode ended I wanted more. See You Space Cowboy…</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="286977">A must see for anyone starting out in the realm of action or sci-fi anime. Definately in my top five list with Trigun, Berserk, Outlaw star and Hellsing for action I would say.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="406803">Legendary ! Charismatic characters, great animation (aired in 1998 !!!), awesome music, great story with action, fun, humor, love... True Masterpiece !</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="199638">Anime masterpiece. Liked both by anime fans and not-anime-lovers. A living legend.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="373896">Everyone should watch this legend.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="414179">Beyond expectations. Puts to shame half of shows i`ve seen so far.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="322928">For me the series has never been topped. Awesome characters, designs, soundtrack and directing as well as a great tie in movie too. For those yet to experience it....you`re missing out</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="23301">Classic must have series.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="113079">A great anime ! A intriguing story , each character with a interesting story .</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="28415">This is one anime I keep watching over and over because it`s so good! And each time I watch it, I find more subtle details to the story...</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="8855">The very pinnacle of all anime....that is all that needs to be said. If perfection existed, this would be it.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="291869">Best I`ve ever seen.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="273014">A must see classic</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="355791">awesome anime great to watch</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="424780">THE.VERY.BEST.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="323986">A top10 anime of all time!!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="142721">This is one of the anime which you MUST see. It`s a classic.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="99944">Simply number one in music , characters , camera work , story. Absolutely must see</recommendation>
</recommendations>
<url>http://www.cowboy-bebop.net/</url>
<creators>
<name id="662" type="Character Design">Kawamoto Toshihiro</name>
<name id="241" type="Music">Kanno Youko</name>
<name id="1352" type="Original Work">Yatate Hajime</name>
<name id="129" type="Direction">Watanabe Shin`ichirou</name>
<name id="662" type="Chief Animation Direction">Kawamoto Toshihiro</name>
<name id="5560" type="Series Composition">Nobumoto Keiko</name>
</creators>
<description>The year is 2071 AD. With the systematic collapse of the old nation-states, a mixed jumble of races and peoples were driven out of their terrestrial Eden and spread to the stars, taking with them the now confused concepts of justice, freedom, violence, and love. New rules were established, and a new generation of bounty hunters came into being. People referred to these bounty hunters as "cowboys".
Meet http://anidb.net/ch270 [Spike Spiegel] and http://anidb.net/ch401 [Jet Black], a drifter and a retired cyborg cop who have started a bounty hunting partnership. In the converted ship The Bebop, Spike and Jet search the galaxy for criminals with bounties on their heads. They meet a lot of interesting characters, including the unusually intelligent dog http://anidb.net/ch403 [Ein], the bizarre hacker child prodigy http://anidb.net/ch402 [Ed], and the voluptuous and vexing femme fatale, http://anidb.net/ch400 [Faye Valentine].
Source: AnimeNfo
Note: Originally aired on http://anidb.net/cr804 [TV Tokyo], but after 12 episodes the show was cancelled due to the violence portrayed in the Cowboy Bebop world and violence in Japanese schools. The final and also the 13th episode on TV Tokyo was a compilation episode where the characters provide a philosophical commentary and end with the words: "[i]This Is Not The End. You Will See The Real "Cowboy Bebop" Someday!" Four months later, http://anidb.net/cr764 [WOWOW] started to broadcast all 26 episodes of Cowboy Bebop. The ordering was different with completely new episodes mixed in between episodes previously broadcast on TV Tokyo, including a new episode 1.[/i]</description>
<ratings>
<permanent count="13225">8.51</permanent>
<temporary count="13585">8.70</temporary>
<review count="22">9.25</review>
</ratings>
<picture>10002.jpg</picture>
<categories>
<category id="198" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Romance</name>
<description>Romance describes a story that deals with love between two or more characters typically also having an optimistic ending. Romance is also a difficulty encountered when creating a harem.</description>
</category>
<category id="454" parentid="4" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Collateral Damage</name>
<description>The usually action orientated anime does not only show large amounts of combat and weapon use, but also the incidental massive destruction of property, often due to the inability of the protagonists to aim properly.

Example: Mecha duking it out in a densely populated urban area.</description>
</category>
<category id="233" parentid="216" hentai="false" weight="300">
<name>Plot Continuity</name>
<description>Consistency of the characteristics of persons, plot, objects, places and events seen by the viewer.&#13;
&#13;
A single linear focused plot is highly continuous.&#13;
&#13;
A truly random plot is highly discontinuous.</description>
</category>
<category id="26" parentid="461" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Post-apocalypse</name>
<description>After a major cataclysm has occurred. World War III, an alien invasion, plague, global warming or some other general disaster are common themes to build a post-apocalyptic world upon, where the effects were severe enough that mankind barely survived.</description>
</category>
<category id="253" parentid="317" hentai="false" weight="300">
<name>Cyberpunk</name>
<description>Cyberpunk focuses on computers or information technology, usually coupled with some degree of breakdown in social order. The plot often centres on a conflict among hackers, artificial intelligences, and mega corporations, tending to be set within a near-future dystopian Earth.</description>
</category>
<category id="174" parentid="8" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Space Travel</name>
<description>Space Travel usually refers going to space or travelling there with or without a spacecraft. There are different forms of space travel like Interplanetary travel, Interstellar travel or Intergalactic travel. Since it isn`t possible to travel faster than light, most anime series involve some sort "sub-space travel mechanism" as a way to travel faster than light.</description>
</category>
<category id="161" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Detective</name>
<description>It focuses on the efforts of the Detective, private investigator or amateur sleuth to solve the mysterious circumstances of a crime by means of clues, investigation, and clever deduction. The successful mystery film often conceals the identity of the perpetrator until late in the story, then adds an element of suspense during the apprehension of the suspect.</description>
</category>
<category id="12" parentid="6" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Future</name>
<description>Anime that fall under the future category are the ones that have a society that could have originated from ours. In most cases it should go hand to hand with sci-fi since we expect the future to consist of advanced technology, however, in the case where it`s explicitly stated in the story that the anime takes place "x years into the future", the state of technology doesn`t matter as long as it`s long into the future. The anime can be set in an alternative universe not tied with our own, as long as it has a futuristic feel to it.&#13;
&#13;
This category sports quite a lot of anime, mostly stemming from SciFi, but not necessarily only from there.</description>
</category>
<category id="129" parentid="19" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Shipboard</name>
<description>Beam me up, Scotty! Space stations (think Death Star) also count. Basically, this category is to tell if the setting takes place onboard a spaceship in space. This category is not applicable if the spaceship lies on a planet and never actually gets into space.</description>
</category>
<category id="19" parentid="7" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Space</name>
<description>The final frontier.</description>
</category>
<category id="205" parentid="295" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Bounty Hunter</name>
<description>A bounty hunter captures fugitives for a monetary reward (bounty). For example the crew in Cowboy Bebop are bounty hunters.</description>
</category>
<category id="8" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Sci-Fi</name>
<description>Science fiction stories usually focus on how situations could be different in the future when we are more technologically advanced; due to either our own achievements or having met with other civilizations whom we have learned from. </description>
</category>
<category id="79" parentid="3" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Seinen</name>
<description>In the context of manga and associated media, the word seinen refers to a male audience roughly between the ages of 15 and 44. In Japanese, the word means simply "young man", and has no anime/manga-related connotations at all. It does not comprise a style or a genre per se, but rather indicates the publisher`s intended target demographic.</description>
</category>
<category id="128" parentid="19" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Other Planet</name>
<description>The anime will fit this category if some or all of the action takes place on another planet which is supposedly in the same universe as Earth, not a complete fantasy world; usually there has to be some concept of space travel. The Latin name for Earth - Terra, would also pass the condition of being in the same universe as Earth. Basically, even mentioning of Earth existing or having existed would be enough. Although Moon is a moon, it also qualifies as Other Planet.</description>
</category>
<category id="263" parentid="4" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Gunfights</name>
<description>Fights where two or more parties are firing guns at one another.</description>
</category>
<category id="4" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Action</name>
<description>Action anime usually involve a fairly straightforward story of good guys versus bad guys, where most disputes are resolved by using physical force. It often contains a lot of shooting, explosions and fighting. </description>
</category>
<category id="275" parentid="268" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>New</name>
<description>Not based on anything, the story is a new work, usually made up by the people involved in creating the anime. Generally if an original work (原作) credit is given, it will be to the studio, or director, or other members of the production team.</description>
</category>
<category id="84" parentid="83" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Violence</name>
<description>Physical force against self or other, compelling action against one`s will on pain of being hurt.</description>
</category>
<category id="235" parentid="317" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Tragedy</name>
<description>Tragedy is a form of drama characterized by seriousness and dignity, usually involving a conflict between a character and some higher power, such as the law, the gods, fate, or society.</description>
</category>
<category id="173" parentid="4" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Swordplay</name>
<description>The act or art of using a sword or similar weapon skillfully.</description>
</category>
<category id="120" parentid="328" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Cyborgs</name>
<description>Cyborgs are humans, who have been taken over in part or in whole by cybernetic or electrical/mechanical devices, which either control them or which they retain control of. The term comes from "CYBernetic ORGganism", which literally means an organism that contains both mechanical and organic components.</description>
</category>
<category id="328" parentid="8" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Human Enhancement</name>
<description>The enhancement of humans can take various forms: It can be something comparatively non-intrusive as a power-up drug, a form of machine implantation or cyberization ("SAC Solid State Society"), or outright - possibly atrocious - genetic manipulation ("Ao no 6-gou"). Plot-wise enhanced protagonists in anime usually have to pay a price for their enhancements, be it physical or mental. </description>
</category>
<category id="15" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Fantasy</name>
<description>Imaginative or fanciful work, especially one dealing with supernatural elements and themes.</description>
</category>
<category id="153" parentid="17" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Slapstick</name>
<description>Slapstick humour is generally recognized by lots of physical abuse, horseplay and practical jokes. Also often seen are impossible situations, using sounds to illustrate impossible stunts that aren`t shown on-screen and to create tension for audience anticipation.</description>
</category>
<category id="225" parentid="256" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Music</name>
<description>Music anime generally revolves around people concerned with music in their everyday lives. In addition they often adhere to certain genre conventions, the emphasis on training and practice in preparation for competitions, characters desire for self improvement, and pursuit of a specific goal. This is not unlike the Sports category.</description>
</category>
<category id="252" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Angst</name>
<description>A feeling of general discomfort and uneasiness is present due to either trivial or more serious reasons, often accompanied by depression.&#13;
&#13;
Warning: may contain copious amounts of brooding and sighing.</description>
</category>
<category id="86" parentid="83" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Sex</name>
<description>Known as intercourse, the ultimate bond of love and the "Origin of the World" (just think of Gustave Courbet`s painting).</description>
</category>
<category id="172" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Thriller</name>
<description>The thriller is a genre of fiction in which tough, resourceful, but essentially ordinary heroes are pitted against villains determined to destroy them, their country, or the stability of the free world. The hero of a typical thriller faces danger alone or in the company of a small band of companions. The protagonist may be a law enforcement agent, a journalist, or a soldier, but typically he or she is cut off from the resources of "their" organization. More often the hero is an ordinary citizen drawn into danger and intrigue by circumstances beyond their control. (Source: Wikipedia)</description>
</category>
<category id="20" parentid="4" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Martial Arts</name>
<description>Characterized by extensive fighting scenes employing various types of martial arts, meaning systems of codified practices and traditions of training for combat.</description>
</category>
<category id="17" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Comedy</name>
<description>Anime whose central struggle causes hilarious results. These stories are built upon funny characters, situations and events. A comedy anime is laced with humour and sets out to provoke laughter from the audience.&#13;
&#13;
Japanese humour can be a bit strange to westerners, so if you`re new to this type of humour, just bear with it; it`ll most likely grow on you if you`re a fan of other kinds of comedy.</description>
</category>
<category id="306" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="300">
<name>Adventure</name>
<description>Adventures are exciting stories, with new experiences or exotic locales. Adventures are designed to provide an action-filled, energetic experience for the viewer. Rather than the predominant emphasis on violence and fighting that is found in pure action anime, however, the viewer of adventures can live vicariously through the travels, conquests, explorations, creation of empires, struggles and situations that confront the main characters, actual historical figures or protagonists. Under the category of adventures, we can include traditional swashbucklers, serialized films, and historical spectacles, searches or expeditions for lost continents, "jungle" and "desert" epics, treasure hunts and quests, disaster films, and heroic journeys or searches for the unknown. Adventure films are often set in an historical period, and may include adapted stories of historical or literary adventure heroes, kings, battles, rebellion, or piracy.</description>
</category>
<category id="424" parentid="328" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Nano Machines</name>
<description>The anime features sub-microscopic (nano = 10E-9 = one billionth) machines, associated with many almost "magical" abilities. E.g. machines that float in the bloodstream, repairing human cells in situ.</description>
</category>
<category id="450" parentid="128" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Mars</name>
<description>The fourth planet from the sun in the solar system.&#13;
&#13;
Popular sci-fi setting for human colonisation and terraforming efforts.</description>
</category>
<category id="459" parentid="340" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Reverse Trap</name>
<description>A girl who dresses in male clothing.</description>
</category>
<category id="504" parentid="17" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Breaking the Fourth Wall</name>
<description>Breaking the fourth wall is the action of addressing or otherwise acknowledging the audience of a work of fiction from within that work, as happens when e.g. the characters of a show speak directly to its viewers. The fourth wall in question is a reference to the imaginary "wall" at the front of the stage of a proscenium theatre, through which the action of the play is seen by the audience; the fourth wall is thus a metaphor for the boundary between what happens inside a fictional work and outside it. This situation is not to be confused with medium awareness, which is when a character shows their awareness of the fact they are a character of a fictional work by e.g. complaining to the writer that they appear in too few episodes.</description>
</category>
</categories>
<resources>
<resource type="1">
<externalentity>
<identifier>13</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="2">
<externalentity>
<identifier>4037</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>17205</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>1</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="3">
<externalentity>
<identifier>114</identifier>
<identifier>tzoabg</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="4">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.sunrise-anime.jp/sunrise-inc/works/detail.php?cid=41</url>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.cowboy-bebop.net/</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="6">
<externalentity>
<identifier>Cowboy_Bebop</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="7">
<externalentity>
<identifier>カウボーイビバップ</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="8">
<externalentity>
<identifier>538</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="9">
<externalentity>
<identifier>88862</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="10">
<externalentity>
<identifier>1628</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
<tags>
<tag id="261" approval="80" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-05-27">
<name>classic</name>
<count>92</count>
<description>It may be a good animation, soundtrack or story or all of them at once or serious lack of them. Whatever the case, this anime deserves its place in the history of Japanese animation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5316" approval="20" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-02-01">
<name>femme fatale</name>
<count>27</count>
<description>The phrase is French for "deadly woman". A femme fatale tries to achieve her hidden purpose by using feminine wiles such as beauty, charm, and sexual allure. Typically, she is exceptionally well-endowed with these qualities. In some situations, she uses lying or coercion rather than charm. She may also be (or imply to be) a victim, caught in a situation from which she cannot escape.
She often leads men into compromising, dangerous, and deadly situations.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="385" approval="60" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-04-14">
<name>great directing</name>
<count>84</count>
<description>This anime is considered to be well cut, in the sense that the director has has made it so that everything fits together as a whole.
This includes but is not limited to: Story, voice acting, music, theme, editing and general feel of the series.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="644" approval="42" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="true" update="2010-03-09">
<name>bittersweet ending</name>
<count>125</count>
<description>The story is over and the bad evil was defeated, but at what price?
Used when the original goal of the story was reached but not without losses. The hero defeats the evil but loses his love, friends, innocence and/or idealistic view, is forgotten by everybody/fades into obscurity despite his heroic deeds or even sacrifices himself and life still goes on for everybody else.
Can be also used in instances where a lover`s couple is broken for the right cause or the protagonist finally decides on his love interest. A bittersweet ending is still ending on a high note, but one that is mixed with sadness and nostalgia.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="716" approval="49" spoiler="true" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="true" update="2010-01-05">
<name>tragic ending</name>
<count>48</count>
</tag>
<tag id="5186" approval="8" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-08-30">
<name>prosthetics</name>
<count>26</count>
<description>A prosthesis (prosthetic) (from Ancient Greek πρόσθεσις, "addition, application, attachment") is a device that replaces a missing body part.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1711" approval="52" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2008-08-07">
<name>space western</name>
<count>9</count>
<description>Space Western is a subgenre of science fiction that transposes themes of American Western books and film to a backdrop of futuristic space frontiers; it is the complement of the science fiction Western, which transposes science fiction themes onto an American Western setting.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="736" approval="17" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-05-22">
<name>Itano Circus</name>
<count>25</count>
<description>The Itano Circus is named after Itano Ichirou, a Japanese animator, and refers to a highly stylized and acrobatic method of depicting aerial combat and dogfights in many anime, particularly the Macross series, where it was utilised by Itano for the first time and was ground-breaking.
The Itano Circus is characterized by detailed, fluid shading of the mecha, the close-range acrobatic moves the duelling fighters make in combat, as well as twisting contrails left by fighters and missiles. It is also commonly used in specific reference to an attack where a mecha or spaceship launches a large swarm of missiles with meticulously animated spiralling smoke trails and erratic trajectories.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3029" approval="12" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-09-03">
<name>detailed and complex world</name>
<count>22</count>
<description>Great care has been taken to create a (often fictional) coherent world or universe.
Such a constructed world may have its own history, technology, languages, etc., creating a more immersive setting for the characters to inhabit and rendering events more meaningful.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="682" approval="65" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2008-06-06">
<name>great soundtrack</name>
<count>382</count>
<description>The anime soundtrack is noteworthy.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2247" approval="19" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-01-31">
<name>heavy smoking</name>
<count>64</count>
<description>Someone in the story consumes more than one supply of their preferred method of inhaled substance by the end of the episode/series.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1803" approval="46" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-10-06">
<name>jazz</name>
<count>8</count>
<description>A style of music originating in the Southern USA in the early 20th century, emerging from Blues and Ragtime. Jazz is often associated with the city of New Orleans.
Jazz music is typified by improvisation and syncopation.
Instruments often associated with Jazz are the trumpet, trombone, piano and clarinet.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1136" approval="27" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-12-16">
<name>great opening</name>
<count>254</count>
<description>This anime contains a wonderful use of animation and/or music/vocals during the opening theme.
Usually, especially the music is quite catchy.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1100" approval="17" spoiler="true" localspoiler="true" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-05-26">
<name>falling star</name>
<count>7</count>
</tag>
<tag id="1861" approval="16" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-06-04">
<name>tomboy</name>
<count>66</count>
<description>A female character that refrains from displaying the usual girlie clichés (e.g. shrill high voice, damsel in distress syndrome, overly prude, air-headed, klutz, wears skimpy clothing, etc.) by acting more mature and "manly". 
Among "boys" she is considered a competent friend, she is simply "one of the boys". Among "girls" she usually plays the role of a protector.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2125" approval="28" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-09-17">
<name>laid-back protagonist</name>
<count>30</count>
<description>The main character doesn`t get excited easily, they seem most at home when doing nothing. With half-shut eyes and near-constant slouching, they sometimes look like they are ready to just fall asleep. Often used to bring greater contrast to the occasions that they do get riled up for.
Examples include Asakura Yoh from Shamen King, and Gintoki from Gintama.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3213" approval="22" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-10-06">
<name>dogfight</name>
<count>20</count>
<description>Dogfight refers to combat engagement between aircraft (or space craft), often one on one. So in short: jets, planes, missiles, machine guns and maybe a kamikaze or two.
Not to be confused with the `bark-bark` or `woof-woof` sort of dogfight.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="753" approval="17" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2008-06-07">
<name>antihero</name>
<count>37</count>
<description>The antihero (sometimes `antiheroine` as feminine) is generally considered to be a protagonist whose character is at least in some regards conspicuously contrary to that of the archetypal hero, and is in some instances its antithesis.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3702" approval="12" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-11-17">
<name>instrumental OP</name>
<count>21</count>
<description>Just music in the opening — no lyrics (vocals) at all.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="252" approval="19" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-08-02">
<name>hacker</name>
<count>26</count>
<description>Individual who breaks into other peoples` computers.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1558" approval="22" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-01-04">
<name>must see classic</name>
<count>75</count>
<description>It`s a classic, YOU MUST SEE IT!</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4428" approval="11" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-02-03">
<name>sense of foreboding</name>
<count>160</count>
<description>The anime starts off quietly, everything seems to be fine, but from episode to episode the signs that something ominous is about to happen increase. E.g. a typical mystery setting.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="755" approval="15" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-01-31">
<name>makes you laugh and cry</name>
<count>53</count>
<description>While watching this series you can expect moments when you fall off your chair laughing, and moments when you will be thankful that there is a pack of tissues nearby. It`s worth mentioning that tears can be caused by touching/drama moments (e.g. Clannad, Hanada Shounen Shi) or "mighty"/overwhelming moments (Tengen Toppa Gurren Lagann).</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3674" approval="8" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-03-20">
<name>awesome villain</name>
<count>20</count>
<description>One or more of the villains in this anime are quite impressive for some reason.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5507" approval="6" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-08-16">
<name>male protagonist</name>
<count>112</count>
<description>These anime have a male protagonist.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1880" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-06-04">
<name>great animation</name>
<count>83</count>
<description>The anime sports exceptionally well made (smooth, detailed, beautiful) animation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5622" approval="8" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-04-21">
<name>ensemble cast</name>
<count>30</count>
<description>The plot focuses on a group of characters rather than a single one.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3272" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-05-26">
<name>drugs</name>
<count>43</count>
</tag>
<tag id="6717" approval="12" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-11-27">
<name>predominantly adult cast</name>
<count>82</count>
<description>This show features mostly adults. That means children and teenagers are relatively rare and unlikely to hold significance to the plot.
That is a rare trait in anime, as most shows spin around children or teenagers.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5790" approval="5" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-02-01">
<name>heavy focus on characters</name>
<count>10</count>
</tag>
<tag id="1859" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-04-23">
<name>bittersweet</name>
<count>32</count>
<description>An anime that is, at the same time, bitter and sweet. In other words, it expresses the conflicting concepts of pain and pleasure through emotions such as melancholy. Said emotions can be either sad or joyful, and oftentimes both sad and joyful at once.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3049" approval="4" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-06-20">
<name>great characters</name>
<count>36</count>
<description>This anime contains character that have a good amount of personality and function in the storyline.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1762" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2008-08-14">
<name>great voice acting</name>
<count>77</count>
<description>The seiyū (voice actors) have done a great job with their talented voices. They breathe life into the character they represent as though expressing their very selves through their animated counter-part.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2543" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-02-19">
<name>awesome main character</name>
<count>134</count>
<description>The show`s main characters deserve to be held in awe — this could be for many reasons including but not limited to ability, personality, strength of character.
Which is good. I mean who wants angst ridden brats for main characters these days anyway?</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1780" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-05-20">
<name>dark atmosphere</name>
<count>61</count>
<description>Usually metaphorical. Sometimes literal. At times both!
Typically this refers to the fact that the story is set in a grim, dog eat dog milieu — for example a decaying city.
Often the characters are just doing what they need to do to survive, with little or no expectation that their lives can be better. And often characters may feel they do not have any real choices in what they do.
And yes, occasionally the setting is actually dark — be it night or perpetual heavy cloud and rain. It all adds to the oppressive, hopeless feeling of the show.
You probably will not feel uplifted or happy after watching this anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="372" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-04-11">
<name>psychological</name>
<count>97</count>
<description>Directed toward dealing with or affecting the mind, especially as a function of awareness, feeling, or motivation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3672" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-01-02">
<name>unique</name>
<count>7</count>
<description>Imagine one day sitting in your chair and oddly staring obliquely. Yet suddenly, in that brief moment of disarray; the clouds of vast nebulae rush past you, unfurling in grand majesty while sprinkling every color imaginable to push your imagination to its fundamental limit.
Yeah, uniqueness is just that.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="860" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-08-10">
<name>despair</name>
<count>35</count>
<description>Involves characters that may be lost in negatively emotional atmospheres created through feelings of hopelessness and suffering.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="838" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false">
<name>melancholic</name>
<count>18</count>
</tag>
<tag id="3841" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2013-02-27">
<name>suffering protagonist</name>
<count>46</count>
<description>The protagonist suffers a lot in the anime and does not seem to be able to overcome it.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2299" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-10-16">
<name>great emotional realism</name>
<count>12</count>
<description>Where the series portrays emotions so vividly, that the audience feels them also.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5485" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="true" update="2009-09-21">
<name>main character dies</name>
<count>28</count>
<description>At least one of the main characters in the anime dies.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1790" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-03-15">
<name>strong male lead</name>
<count>82</count>
<description>The lead male protagonist in this anime shows backbone, is competent, and does not shy away from seemingly insurmountable objectives.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="7368" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2013-04-30">
<name>blues</name>
<count>1</count>
</tag>
<tag id="645" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-05-22">
<name>comic relief animal sidekick</name>
<count>226</count>
<description>Every mahou shoujo anime needs them, the cute little critters that are supposed to help the protagonists but in reality are nothing but useless bystanders most often abused for gags. Kids love them but they can also often turn into an annoyance.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3522" approval="13" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2011-01-13">
<name>heterochromia</name>
<count>106</count>
<description>Heterochromia Iridis is a medical condition, where an individual has at least an eye with more than one colour or two eyes of entirely different colours.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="810" approval="5" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-10-06">
<name>epic</name>
<count>163</count>
<description>Epic is all about scale. Whether it is the vastness of the anime’s universe, the grandeur of the protagonist’s heroic journey, or the anime’s over-the-top, pulse-pounding visual style — when the anime becomes larger than life and draws the viewer in with an overwhelming sense of awe, it can be described simply as Epic.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5315" approval="16" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-02-01">
<name>neo-noir</name>
<count>9</count>
<description>Neo-noir is a style often seen in modern motion pictures and other forms that prominently utilizes elements of film noir, but with updated themes, content, style, visual elements or media that were absent in films noir of the 1940s and 1950s.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="827" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-05-28">
<name>lost technology</name>
<count>79</count>
<description>Any advanced technology or science-related knowledge that was lost for some reason fits the description. This could be technology from a time before a post-apocalyptic cataclysm, knowledge gained a long time ago but forgotten, or the relics of an old alien civilization only recently discovered.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="789" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-10-03">
<name>massacre</name>
<count>72</count>
<description>Mass murder.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1553" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-06-23">
<name>car chases</name>
<count>38</count>
<description>Car chases occur as part of the action setting in this anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5891" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2013-07-10">
<name>dogs</name>
<count>47</count>
<description>The dog is carnivorous mammal and a subspecies of the gray wolf. Dogs were the first domesticated animal and have been the most widely kept working, hunting, and pet animal in human history. Their value to early human hunter-gatherers quickly made them ubiquitous. They perform many roles for people, and their impact on human society nicknamed them "man`s best friend" in the Western world. Most dog breeds have been developed through selective breeding for particular morphologies and behaviours.</description>
</tag>
</tags>
<characters>
<character id="270" type="main character in" update="2013-06-10">
<rating votes="556">9.30</rating>
<name>Spike Spiegel</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A former member of the Red Dragons mafia group, Spike left his past behind 3 years ago and now lives the life of a wanderer, sailing the cosmos alongside his trusted partner, Jet Black, in their ship, the Bebop. Always after a new prize to restock their dwindling money supply and put food on the table, Spike and Jet will get into all sorts of scrapes to hunt criminals down. Spike`s skills at martial arts and with his gun help make him someone you definitely do not want to mess with.</description>
<picture>14555.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="380" picture="38028.jpg">Yamadera Kouichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="400" type="main character in" update="2013-08-13">
<rating votes="250">7.69</rating>
<name>Faye Valentine</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Faye Valentine is one of the members of the bounty hunting crew in the anime series Cowboy Bebop. She is often seen with a cigarette and in a revealing outfit complete with bright yellow hot pants and a matching, revealing top (and, on occasion, a bikini). She sports violet hair, green eyes, and a voluptuous body. Although appearing to be no more than 23 years old, Faye is actually around 77 years old, having been put into cryogenic freeze after a space shuttle accident, wherein she spent fifty-four years in suspended animation. During the course of the series (set in 2071), Faye manages to cross paths with Spike and Jet twice before she finally makes herself at home aboard their ship the second time around, much to the consternation and disapproval of the two men, both of whom have their own reservations about women in general.
Faye herself is brash, egotistical, and quite lazy, despite taking plenty of time to pamper and care for her own appearance. Faye has been arrested several times in the series, and has spent time in handcuffs on the ship. She, at times, expects the boys to take care of bounties for her, while she sits by idly to reap the benefits and eat all their food, which is another source of conflict.
Seemingly little more than a thorn in her partner`s sides, Faye is actually a well-rounded member of the team. She can handle herself exceptionally well for a woman of her slight appearance, displaying at least once in the series (in "Cowboy Funk") that she has a powerful punch. Adept at flying, Faye has stood her ground just as well as Spike has in an aerial dogfight in her ship Red Tail, and at times even against Spike in an aerial dogfight (though Spike eventually proved the better pilot). She also excels with guns, and is first seen in the series completely disabling a shop with a Heckler &amp; Koch MP5K, though she is immediately apprehended afterward. In the movie, she is seen with the same gun, in addition to her normal companion: a Glock 30. Faye has an almost unstoppable attitude, and even her sometimes innocent smile can be seen as dangerous. She has many bad habits, such as drinking, habitual gambling, smoking cigarettes and occasionally cigars, becoming unnecessarily violent, and turning on partners when the profits seem too skimpy. Sarcastic and presumptuous, she rarely appears weak or in need of support. She brags and takes care of herself, never trusting others, cheating and lying her way from one day to the next.
She is a woman who is skilled at getting what she wants; her indomitable exterior hides a more delicate interior. Upon awakening from her 54-year cryogenic sleep, not only was she saddled with a massive amount of debt that she had no means to pay, but she was also diagnosed with total amnesia, a stranger in a mysterious world that she was not a part of and did not understand, surrounded by people who claimed to be helping her but were only there to take advantage of her naiveté. The surname "Valentine" was merely a name given to her by the doctor who woke her; the circumstances of her accident, her previous life, and even her real name all remain a mystery, and are only gradually revealed as the series progresses. It has been hinted that she came from Singapore on Earth, and was the daughter of a very wealthy family, as the city`s famous Merlion Statue features prominently in scenes of her childhood, and that memories and a film from her childhood showed her living in a large mansion. Faye is supposedly her real name, as a high school classmate (by now an old disabled woman) recognizes her and calls her by that name. In her debut episode, she claims to be descended from Roma people, but it later becomes apparent that was likely a lie. Utterly betrayed by someone she thought she could trust after waking, Faye found herself burdened with even more money to pay, and the situation resulted in the hardening of her personality to an extreme degree. She even says in Session 11: "we deceive or we are deceived", and that "nothing good ever happened to me when I trusted others."
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>14672.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="13" picture="16583.jpg">Hayashibara Megumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="401" type="main character in" update="2013-08-05">
<rating votes="160">7.49</rating>
<name>Jet Black</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Known on his home satellite as the "Black Dog" for his tenacity, Jet Black is a 36-year-old former cop from Ganymede (a Jovian satellite) and acts as Spike`s foil during the series. Physically, Jet is very tall with a muscular build. He wears a beard with no mustache, and is completely bald save for the back of his head. Spike acts lazy and uninterested, whereas Jet is hard working and a jack-of-all-trades. Jet was once an investigator in the Intra Solar System Police (ISSP) for many years until he lost his arm in an investigation that went awry when his corrupt partner (and friend at the time) betrayed him. His arm was replaced with a cybernetic limb—an operation later revealed to be by choice. As biological replacements were possible, he wanted the fake arm as a reminder of the consequences of his actions. His loss of limb coupled with the general corruption of the police force prompted Jet to quit the ISSP in disgust and become a freelance bounty hunter. Jet also considers himself something of a renaissance man: he cultivates bonsai trees, cooks, enjoys jazz/blues music (he named his ship the Bebop, referring to a type of jazz), especially Charlie Parker, and even has interest in Goethe. As a character, Jet is the quintessential oyaji or "dad" even though he often wishes people would view him as a more brotherly figure (so as not to seem old). Of the crew he shows the most obvious affection when dealing with Edward, most obviously shown when he tells her a story in Session 18; he is also shown attempting to (perhaps falsely) reassure himself after she and Faye leave the crew of the Bebop, hinting that his sometimes-stoic nature may be born of necessity rather than any real lack of emotion.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>14673.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="339" picture="79312.jpg">Ishizuka Unshou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="402" type="main character in" update="2013-08-05">
<rating votes="214">7.58</rating>
<name>Edward Wong Hau Pepelu Tivrusky IV</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Edward Wong Hau Pepelu Tivruski IV is the self-invented personal name of an elite hacker prodigy from Earth. Her birth name is Françoise Appledehli. "Radical Edward" is a very strange, somewhat androgynous, teenage girl claiming to be around 13 years of age. Her mannerisms include walking around in her bare feet, performing strange postures, and her gangling walk. Ed could be considered a "free spirit;" she is fond of silly exclamations and childish rhymes, is easily distracted, has the habit of "drifting off" from reality... sometimes in mid-sentence, and is the show`s primary source of physical humor. Ed`s generally carefree attitude and energy act as a counterpoint to the more solemn and dark aspects of the show. Ed remains a part of the Bebop crew until the 24th episode, when she, along with Ein, leaves the crew to reunite with her father.
Over the course of the show, she rarely walks anywhere, preferring to run, crawl, flip, roll, walk on her hands, ride piggy-back, or, at the very least, saunter. Ed wears a very loose sleeveless shirt and tight, black bicycle shorts, and a pair of large green goggles around her neck or on her head that act as a virtual reality accessory for computers when connected. She is always barefoot and uses her feet for tasks which one would usually use hands, such as scratching her nose, clapping, and typing, and it seems she has followed this habit throughout her life. This also works the other way around, where she walks on her hands instead of her feet. In the episode Mushroom Samba she considers putting on socks and shoes but quickly removes them, as even wearing socks hampers her, and she falls over seconds after putting them on.
She almost always refers to herself in the third person. Not much is known about her origins, only that she spent some of her earlier childhood in an orphanage after being left there by her father, a cartographer (a questionable occupation on a planet which undergoes changes to its landscape daily due to asteroid impacts) named Appledelhi Siniz Hesap Lütfen (which means "excuse me, check please" in Turkish). Ed`s primary use to the Bebop crew is as a hacker; she is widely known to be a whiz kid behind the computer. Ed`s computer of choice is a carry-along Tomato desktop, and when traveling by foot she will balance it on her head. Her goggles can interact with it to give her a virtual reality environment in which she can browse an entire network at once.
Source: Wiki</description>
<picture>14676.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="405" picture="17252.jpg">Tada Aoi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="403" type="secondary cast in" update="2008-12-10">
<rating votes="103">8.12</rating>
<name>Ein</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>14678.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="380" picture="38028.jpg">Yamadera Kouichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="404" type="secondary cast in" update="2008-12-10">
<rating votes="50">6.20</rating>
<name>Vicious</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>14684.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2" picture="16471.jpg">Wakamoto Norio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="405" type="secondary cast in" update="2008-12-10">
<rating votes="39">4.05</rating>
<name>Julia</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>14687.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="404" picture="23900.jpg">Takashima Gara</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="10212" type="appears in" update="2009-07-06">
<rating votes="30">8.51</rating>
<name>Bebop Gou Crew</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="3">Organization</charactertype>
<description>The crew of the spaceship Bebop are a partnership of bounty hunters, called "cowboys". Originally consisted of Jet Black and Spike Spiegel, later Faye Valentine, Ed (Edward Wong Hau Pepelu Tivrusky IV) and Ein have joined.</description>
<picture>30643.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="10219" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="12">7.73</rating>
<name>Bebop</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="4">Vessel</charactertype>
<description>A former fishing trawler spaceship owned by Jet Black and refitted to serve as a mobile base for bounty hunting. Contains enough living space to house at least 4 people and one dog. Bebop isn`t equipped with any kind of defensive or offensive weaponry but internal hangars may uphold at least 3 fighter class ships. It is also capable of interplanetary jumpgate travel and planet water landing.</description>
<picture>30652.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2089" picture="21473.jpg">Morota Kaoru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18655" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">6.04</rating>
<name>Bartender</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49382.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3102" picture="24178.jpg">Chou Katsumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18656" type="appears in" update="2013-01-12">
<rating votes="6">4.61</rating>
<name>Asimov Solensan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49383.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="18719" picture="68967.jpg">Nishi Tarou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18657" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">5.30</rating>
<name>Laughing Bull</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49384.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4683" picture="27279.jpg">Koyama Takehiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18659" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="6">7.33</rating>
<name>Katerina</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49386.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2879" picture="29142.jpg">Hino Yurika</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18660" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="3">2.33</rating>
<name>Abdul Hakim</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49388.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2053" picture="23204.jpg">Ootomo Ryuuzaburou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18662" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="10">6.39</rating>
<name>Judy</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49390.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="290" picture="24139.jpg">Nagasawa Miki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18663" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="5">5.88</rating>
<name>Punch</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49391.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2199" picture="21752.jpg">Tareki Tsutomu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18664" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Owner</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49392.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3968" picture="22867.jpg">Mizuhara Rin</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18665" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Oyaji</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49394.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="18720" picture="49379.jpg">Hirao Jinshou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18670" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">2.06</rating>
<name>Gordon</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49402.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="544" picture="17749.jpg">Ogawa Shinji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18675" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">1.99</rating>
<name>Morgan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49408.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="242" picture="38156.jpg">Nakata Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18676" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="4">1.82</rating>
<name>Twinkle Maria Murdock</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49409.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="18731" picture="49407.jpg">Arita Mari</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18677" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Harrison</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49410.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="173" picture="39411.jpg">Chafuurin</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18681" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="6">6.87</rating>
<name>Bob</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49415.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="415" picture="72865.jpg">Nakano Yutaka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18682" type="appears in" update="2010-06-09">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Choukan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49417.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="275" picture="17102.jpg">Tahara Aruno</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18683" type="appears in" update="2013-01-13">
<rating votes="3">3.15</rating>
<name>Mao Yenrai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49428.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4690" picture="49427.jpg">Itou Kazuaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18684" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="4">4.07</rating>
<name>Annie</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49429.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="494" picture="17485.jpg">Ichijou Miyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18692" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Fatty</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49475.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2946" picture="23373.jpg">Gouri Daisuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18693" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="3">4.50</rating>
<name>Giraffe</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49476.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3276" picture="24272.jpg">Nakagi Ryuuji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18694" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="2">4.33</rating>
<name>Zebra</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49477.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="18695" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="4">3.02</rating>
<name>Wen</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49478.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1446" picture="19314.jpg">Touma Yumi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18696" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="4">5.02</rating>
<name>VT</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49480.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2276" picture="21923.jpg">Kataoka Tomie</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18697" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="3">4.17</rating>
<name>Macho</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49481.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="242" picture="38156.jpg">Nakata Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18698" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="4">3.78</rating>
<name>Muriel</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49482.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4957" picture="91922.jpg">Uchikawa Ai</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18699" type="appears in" update="2010-06-11">
<rating votes="2">4.33</rating>
<name>Otto</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49483.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="601" picture="18008.jpg">Nakamura Hidetoshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18726" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="5">5.68</rating>
<name>Roco</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49524.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3149" picture="132209.jpg">Nakao Ryuusei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18727" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="1">2.15</rating>
<name>Louie</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49525.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1756" picture="53985.jpg">Nakajima Toshihiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18728" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="1">1.43</rating>
<name>Huey</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49526.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2021" picture="30870.jpg">Tsuji Shinpachi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18729" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="2">4.13</rating>
<name>Dewey</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49527.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="25084" picture="28798.jpg">Hayami Kei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18730" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="5">3.87</rating>
<name>Stella</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49528.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="227" picture="17046.jpg">Sakamoto Maaya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18732" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="1">2.15</rating>
<name>Piccaro</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49529.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2823" picture="83143.jpg">Shimaka Yuu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18733" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="2">4.68</rating>
<name>Announcer 2</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49533.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="628" picture="18153.jpg">Dodo Asako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18734" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="2">2.51</rating>
<name>Amjad</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49534.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2021" picture="30870.jpg">Tsuji Shinpachi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18735" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="3">5.46</rating>
<name>MPU</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The satellite control program on the D-135 artificial sattelite which Ed names MPU.</description>
<picture>49537.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="226" picture="17045.jpg">Nakata Jouji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18738" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="2">3.32</rating>
<name>Donelly</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49540.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4478" picture="26750.jpg">Matsuoka Fumio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18740" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="7">6.35</rating>
<name>Arisa</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49544.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="18753" type="appears in" update="2010-06-12">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Rhint</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49560.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="254" picture="17073.jpg">Yamaguchi Kappei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18764" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="3">4.97</rating>
<name>Lin</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49627.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="353" picture="17192.jpg">Midorikawa Hikaru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18765" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="3">2.04</rating>
<name>Man Long</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49629.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="27206" picture="73948.jpg">Taguchi Takashi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18766" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="3">1.18</rating>
<name>Julius</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49631.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4841" picture="55063.jpg">Iwasaki Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18767" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="8">6.02</rating>
<name>Gren</name>
<gender>intersexual</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49632.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2037" picture="21371.jpg">Horiuchi Ken`yuu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18768" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="2">5.04</rating>
<name>Bartender</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49633.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1913" picture="26099.jpg">Chiba Isshin</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18769" type="appears in" update="2011-02-28">
<rating votes="2">6.04</rating>
<name>Bartender</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>66706.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="282" picture="17112.jpg">Houki Katsuhisa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18770" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="3">3.78</rating>
<name>Otoko</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49640.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2340" picture="22090.jpg">Naka Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18771" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Kodomo</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49642.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="290" picture="24139.jpg">Nagasawa Miki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18786" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="2">3.32</rating>
<name>Jonathan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49645.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3317" picture="24700.jpg">Kishino Yukimasa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18787" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="3">6.27</rating>
<name>Chessmaster Hex</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49646.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3225" picture="24205.jpg">Watabe Takeshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18788" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Doctor Baccus</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49647.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="18789" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Whitney Hagas Matsumoto</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49648.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="286" picture="17117.jpg">Ootsuka Akio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18790" type="appears in" update="2010-06-13">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Manley</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49649.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4770" picture="76766.jpg">Suzuka Chiharu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18811" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="3">2.61</rating>
<name>Yuuri Kellerman</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49681.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="368" picture="25838.jpg">Tatsuta Naoki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18824" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="2">2.08</rating>
<name>Pilot</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49694.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2246" picture="21809.jpg">Mikimoto Yuuji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18825" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="3">1.79</rating>
<name>Dig</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49695.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2823" picture="83143.jpg">Shimaka Yuu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18826" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Fad</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49697.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="418" picture="17270.jpg">Hirose Masashi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18827" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="4">5.02</rating>
<name>Udai</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49696.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4688" picture="29259.jpg">Hirota Kousei</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18828" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="4">5.30</rating>
<name>Kofi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49698.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="222" picture="19786.jpg">Tanaka Atsuko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18829" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Domino Walker</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49699.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="343" picture="140430.jpg">Genda Tesshou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18830" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="1">3.43</rating>
<name>Shaft</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49700.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="297" picture="17126.jpg">Ootsuka Houchuu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18834" type="appears in" update="2010-06-14">
<rating votes="2">4.52</rating>
<name>Video Mania</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49704.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="541" picture="26117.jpg">Chiba Shigeru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18845" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">4.79</rating>
<name>Miles</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49727.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="107" picture="16713.jpg">Shioya Yoku</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18846" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">6.27</rating>
<name>Duhan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49725.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="28" picture="23184.jpg">Aono Takeshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18847" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="1">3.43</rating>
<name>Ruth</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49726.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="67" picture="25195.jpg">Ishii Kouji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18848" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="1">3.43</rating>
<name>Reggie</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49728.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2340" picture="22090.jpg">Naka Hiroshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18849" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>George</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49729.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1998" picture="21301.jpg">Nagasako Takashi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18850" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">3.78</rating>
<name>Harman</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49730.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="233" picture="17051.jpg">Miki Shin`ichirou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18851" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="4">7.21</rating>
<name>Tongpu</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49731.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2782" picture="23189.jpg">Ginga Banjou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18852" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Tenshi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49732.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="643" picture="18170.jpg">Kojima Sachiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18853" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="4">5.27</rating>
<name>Meifa</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49733.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="457" picture="61775.jpg">Ogasawara Arisa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18854" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="2">3.47</rating>
<name>Pao</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49736.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2366" picture="22145.jpg">Ooki Tamio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18856" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="16">6.51</rating>
<name>Andy von de Oniyate</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Part of the YMCA, the Young Men`s Cowboy Association!</description>
<picture>49737.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="467" picture="38026.jpg">Ebara Masashi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18857" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">5.59</rating>
<name>Teddy Bomber</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49739.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="614" picture="18136.jpg">Hashi Takaya</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18873" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="1">3.43</rating>
<name>Reporter</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49760.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="21499" picture="55570.jpg">Tomokawa Mari</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18874" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="1">3.43</rating>
<name>Caster</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49759.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="29936" picture="79160.jpg">Kogami Hiromichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18875" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">1.91</rating>
<name>Londes</name>
<gender>none/does not apply</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49761.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="456" picture="17358.jpg">Ootsuka Chikao</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18876" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">3.28</rating>
<name>Keibiin</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A guard.</description>
<picture>49762.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3315" picture="24335.jpg">Mizuuchi Kiyomitsu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18877" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="2">5.78</rating>
<name>Ronny Spanngen</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49763.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20240" picture="68989.jpg">Hachinohe Masaru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18878" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">4.90</rating>
<name>Mago</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49766.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="6685" picture="31329.jpg">Asano Ruri</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18879" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">4.50</rating>
<name>Sally Yung</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49767.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5352" picture="134103.jpg">Tani Ikuko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18880" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">3.38</rating>
<name>McEntire</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49765.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2218" picture="21761.jpg">Nakahara Shigeru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18881" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="5">5.88</rating>
<name>Appledelhi Siniz Hesap Lutfen</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Correctly transcribed name: Appledelhi Siniz Hesap Lütfen.</description>
<picture>49764.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="23" picture="16605.jpg">Utsumi Kenji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18882" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="4">4.29</rating>
<name>Doctor</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49768.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3135" picture="24120.jpg">Fujimoto Yuzuru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18883" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="2">2.62</rating>
<name>Hahaoya</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49770.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2255" picture="38626.jpg">Okamoto Yoshiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="18887" type="appears in" update="2010-06-15">
<rating votes="3">4.97</rating>
<name>Shin</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>49778.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="73" picture="58662.jpg">Hiyama Nobuyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="19068" type="appears in" update="2010-06-20">
<rating votes="2">1.61</rating>
<name>Irezumi Otoko</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>50087.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="168" picture="80607.jpg">Fujiwara Keiji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="19146" type="appears in" update="2010-06-23">
<rating votes="2">4.33</rating>
<name>Baker Panchorero</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A criminal from Mars who broke into a bank.</description>
<picture>50242.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="282" picture="17112.jpg">Houki Katsuhisa</seiyuu>
</character>
</characters>
<episodes>
<episode id="858" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">19</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-03-06</airdate>
<rating votes="36">6.09</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ワイルド・ホーセス</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Wild Horses</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Auf Abfangkurs</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Caballos Salvajes</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Dzikie konie</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Cavalls Salvatges</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Amit ma elkaphatsz, ne halaszd holnapra</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Wild Horses</title>
</episode>
<episode id="859" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">18</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-06-19</airdate>
<rating votes="41">8.98</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">スピーク・ライク・ア・チャイルド</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Speak Like a Child</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Post aus der Vergangenheit</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Habla como un Niño</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Mówić jak dziecko</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Parla com una Nena</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">A videóüzenet</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Speak Like a Child</title>
</episode>
<episode id="860" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">17</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-02-20</airdate>
<rating votes="47">9.05</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">マッシュルーム・サンバ</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Mushroom Samba</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Breiter als das Universum</title>
<title xml:lang="es">La Samba de las Setas</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Grzybowa samba</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">La Samba del Bolets</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Gomba szamba</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Mushroom Samba</title>
</episode>
<episode id="861" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">16</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-02-13</airdate>
<rating votes="39">8.07</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ブラック・ドッグ・セレナーデ</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Black Dog Serenade</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Der falsche Freund</title>
<title xml:lang="es">La Serenata del Perro Negro</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Serenada czarnego psa</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">La Serenata del Gos Negre</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Fegyencjárat</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Black Dog Serenade</title>
</episode>
<episode id="862" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">15</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-06-12</airdate>
<rating votes="36">7.50</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">マイ・ファニー・ヴァレンタイン</title>
<title xml:lang="en">My Funny Valentine</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Dornröschen, eisgekühlt</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Mi Querida Valentine</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Moja Fanny Valentine</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">La Divertida Valentine</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Űr Don Juan</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">My Funny Valentine</title>
</episode>
<episode id="863" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">14</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-06-05</airdate>
<rating votes="33">7.56</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ボヘミアン・ラプソディー</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Bohemian Rhapsody</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Schachmatt</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Rapsodia Bohemia</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Bohemian Rapsody</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Rapsòdia Bohèmia</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">A sakkmester</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Bohemian Rhapsody</title>
</episode>
<episode id="864" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">9</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-05-01</airdate>
<rating votes="40">7.45</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ジャミング・ウィズ・エドワード</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Jamming with Edward</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Genie und Wahnsinn</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Interferencias de EDO</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Spotkanie z Edem</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Els Embolics de l`Eduard</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">A magányos számítógép</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Jamming with Edward</title>
</episode>
<episode id="865" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">13</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-05-29</airdate>
<rating votes="43">9.41</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ジュピター・ジャズ (後編)</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Jupiter Jazz Part II</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die Tränen des Kriegers (Teil 2)</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Júpiter Jazz (2da Parte)</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Jowiszowy jazz, część 2</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">El Jazz de Júpiter (2a. part)</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Halál Jazz</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Jupiter Jazz (Kouhen)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="866" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">8</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-04-24</airdate>
<rating votes="42">7.82</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ワルツ・フォー・ヴィーナス</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Waltz for Venus</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Geschwisterliebe</title>
<title xml:lang="es">El Vals de Venus</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Walc na Wenus</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">El Vals de Venus</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Kaland a Vénusz bolygón</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Waltz for Venus</title>
</episode>
<episode id="867" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">12</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-05-22</airdate>
<rating votes="44">9.24</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ジュピター・ジャズ (前編)</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Jupiter Jazz Part I</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die Tränen des Kriegers (Teil 1)</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Júpiter Jazz (1ª Parte)</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Jowiszowy jazz, część 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">El Jazz de Júpiter (1a. part)</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Jupiter Jazz</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Jupiter Jazz (Zenpen)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="868" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">7</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-04-17</airdate>
<rating votes="44">5.28</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ヘヴィ・メタル・クイーン</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Heavy Metal Queen</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Der Abschaum der Galaxis</title>
<title xml:lang="es">La Reina del Heavy Metal</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Królowa heavy metalu</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">La Reina del Heavy Metal</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Űrkamionosok</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Heavy Metal Queen</title>
</episode>
<episode id="869" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">11</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-05-15</airdate>
<rating votes="53">9.32</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">闇夜のヘヴィ・ロック</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Toys in the Attic</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die galaktische Killer-Bestie</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Los Juguetes del Desván</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Zabawki na strychu</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Les Joguines de les Golfes</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Harapós kísértet</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Yamiyo no Heavy Rock</title>
</episode>
<episode id="870" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">6</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-11-28</airdate>
<rating votes="44">6.58</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">悪魔を憐れむ歌</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Sympathy for the Devil</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Der Junge mit der Mundharmonika</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Simpatía por el Diablo</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Współczucie dla diabła</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Compassió pel Diable</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Kisördög ez a gyerek</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Akuma o Awaremu Uta</title>
</episode>
<episode id="871" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">10</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-05-08</airdate>
<rating votes="42">7.36</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ガニメデ慕情</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Ganymede Elegy</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Verloren und verlassen</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Elegía de Ganímedes</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Elegia na Ganimedesa</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">L`elegia de Ganimedes</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Végállomás</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Ganymede Bojou</title>
</episode>
<episode id="872" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">26</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-04-24</airdate>
<rating votes="62">9.56</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ザ・リアル・フォークブルース (後編)</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Real Folk Blues Part II</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die letzte Mission</title>
<title xml:lang="es">El Auténtico Folk Blues (2da Parte)</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Prawdziwy blues, część 2</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">L`Autèntic Folk Blues (II)</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Az álom véget ér</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">The Real Folk Blues (Kouhen)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="873" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">5</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-11-21</airdate>
<rating votes="64">9.27</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">堕天使たちのバラッド</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Ballad of Fallen Angels</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Böses Blut</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Balada de los Ángeles Caídos</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Ballada o upadłych aniołach</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">La Balada dels Àngels Caiguts</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Spike rejtett titka</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Datenshi-tachi no Ballad</title>
</episode>
<episode id="874" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">25</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-04-17</airdate>
<rating votes="45">9.48</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ザ・リアル・フォークブルース (前編)</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Real Folk Blues Part I</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Der Machtkampf</title>
<title xml:lang="es">El Auténtico Folk Blues (1era Parte)</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Prawdziwy blues, część 1</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">L`Autèntic Folk Blues (I)</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">A Vörös Sárkányok</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">The Real Folk Blues (Zenpen)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="875" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">4</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-11-14</airdate>
<rating votes="46">5.78</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ゲイトウェイ・シャッフル</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Gateway Shuffle</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Rettet die Wasserratten!</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Puerta de Escape</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Problem z wrotami</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Porta de Fugida</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Majomkodók</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Gateway Shuffle</title>
</episode>
<episode id="876" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">24</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-04-10</airdate>
<rating votes="41">9.77</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ハード・ラック・ウーマン</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Hard Luck Woman</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Die totale Erinnerung</title>
<title xml:lang="es">El Destino de la Mujer es Duro</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Smutna kobieta</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">El Destí de la Dona és Dur</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Tudnod kell, ki vagy</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Hard Luck Woman</title>
</episode>
<episode id="877" update="2005-06-09">
<epno type="1">3</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-04-10</airdate>
<rating votes="47">6.60</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ホンキィ・トンク・ウィメン</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Honky Tonk Women</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Zickenalarm</title>
<title xml:lang="es">La Jugadora</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Honky-tonk women</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">La Jugadora</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Nő a baj</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Honky Tonk Women</title>
</episode>
<episode id="878" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">23</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-04-03</airdate>
<rating votes="35">8.94</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ブレイン・スクラッチ</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Brain Scratch</title>
<title xml:lang="de">In den Fängen der Sekte</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Arañazo Cerebral</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Umysłowe marzenie</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Rascada Cerebral</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Szellem a gépben</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Brain Scratch</title>
</episode>
<episode id="879" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">2</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-04-03</airdate>
<rating votes="51">5.45</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">野良犬のストラット</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Stray Dog Strut</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Ein tierisches Geschäft</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Strut Perro Callejero</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Zbłąkany pies</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">El Gos de Carrer</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Kincs ez a kutya</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Norainu no Strut</title>
</episode>
<episode id="880" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">22</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-03-27</airdate>
<rating votes="35">8.83</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">カウボーイ・ファンク</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Cowboy Funk</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Das Duell</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Mejor Cowboy</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Kowbojski funk</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Cowboy Funk</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Fejvadász a cowboy ellen</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Cowboy Funk</title>
</episode>
<episode id="881" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">1</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1998-10-24</airdate>
<rating votes="77">6.58</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">アステロイド・ブルース</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Asteroid Blues</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Der tödliche Deal</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Canción Triste para un Asteroide</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Asteroidalny blues</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">El Blues de l`Asteroide</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Bolygóközi blues</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Asteroid Blues</title>
</episode>
<episode id="882" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">21</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-03-20</airdate>
<rating votes="30">6.32</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ブギ・ウギ・フンシェイ</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Boogie-Woogie Feng-Shui</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Das Geheimnis der Sonnensteine</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Boggie Woogie Feng Shui</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Boogie Woogie Feng Shui</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Boogie Woogie Feng-Shui</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">Boogie Woogie Feng Shui</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Boogie-Woogie Feng-Shui</title>
</episode>
<episode id="883" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="1">20</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>1999-03-13</airdate>
<rating votes="43">9.13</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">道化師の鎮魂歌</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Pierrot Le Fou</title>
<title xml:lang="de">Der lachende Tod</title>
<title xml:lang="es">Pierrot Le Fou</title>
<title xml:lang="pl">Szalony Piotruś</title>
<title xml:lang="ca">Pierrot el Boig</title>
<title xml:lang="hu">A bohóc</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Doukeshi no Chinkonka</title>
</episode>
<episode id="7274" recap="true" update="2013-03-26">
<epno type="2">S1</epno>
<length>30</length>
<airdate>1998-06-26</airdate>
<rating votes="10">5.73</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">よせあつめブルース</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Session XX: Mish-Mash Blues</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Yoseatsume Blues</title>
</episode>
<episode id="22748" update="2011-02-03">
<epno type="4">T1</epno>
<length>1</length>
<rating votes="1">1.44</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Session 00 (Characters)</title>
</episode>
<episode id="23130" update="2005-08-22">
<epno type="2">S2</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Kanno Youko Interview</title>
</episode>
<episode id="36590" update="2006-02-09">
<epno type="4">T9</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Session 09 Preview</title>
</episode>
<episode id="36634" update="2006-02-09">
<epno type="4">T6</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Session 06 Preview</title>
</episode>
<episode id="46674" update="2006-02-07">
<epno type="4">T7</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Session 07 Preview</title>
</episode>
<episode id="46675" update="2006-02-07">
<epno type="4">T8</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Session 08 Preview</title>
</episode>
<episode id="118920" update="2010-06-11">
<epno type="3">C2</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>1998-10-24</airdate>
<rating votes="1">9.74</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 1</title>
</episode>
<episode id="118921" update="2010-06-11">
<epno type="3">C1</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>1998-10-24</airdate>
<rating votes="1">9.74</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening</title>
</episode>
<episode id="120855" update="2010-08-06">
<epno type="3">C4</epno>
<length>0</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 3</title>
</episode>
<episode id="120856" update="2010-08-06">
<epno type="3">C3</epno>
<length>0</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="127868" update="2011-10-20">
<epno type="2">S3</epno>
<length>30</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Session 0</title>
</episode>
<episode id="147212" update="2013-02-03">
<epno type="2">S4</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Ein`s Summer Vacation</title>
</episode>
<episode id="155750" update="2013-11-02">
<epno type="4">T10</epno>
<length>2</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Blu-Ray Commercial</title>
</episode>
<episode id="155751" update="2013-11-02">
<epno type="2">S6</epno>
<length>5</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Tank! Bebop AV Edit</title>
</episode>
<episode id="155752" update="2013-11-02">
<epno type="2">S5</epno>
<length>4</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Tank! Full Size Music Clip</title>
</episode>
</episodes>
</anime>
